美国家庭影院 出品
联合制作: 梦工厂 与 PLAYTON公司
领衔主演:科克・阿塞沃多 迈克尔・库德利兹 戴尔・戴伊
里克・格梅兹 斯科特・格里米斯 弗兰克・休伊斯
达米安・路易斯 朗・利文斯通 詹姆斯・马迪奥
尼尔・麦克唐纳 理察・斯贝特 谢恩・泰勒
与:唐尼・沃尔伯格
角色的分派: 利伯曼/巴顿
视觉效果总监:安格斯・ 比克尔顿
特殊效果监督员: 乔斯・威廉姆斯
服装设计师: 安娜・谢帕德
剪辑:约翰・理查兹
音乐:迈克尔・凯曼
制作设计 : 安东尼・布拉特
摄影指导: 雷米・阿德法拉欣
监督指导: 艾力克・简得森
制作人: 玛丽・理查兹
监督制片人: 埃里克・ 柏克
联合执行制片人: 史蒂芬・安布洛斯 加里・高依兹曼 托尼・ 托
执行制片人:汤姆・汉克斯 斯蒂文・斯皮尔伯格
兄弟连作者: 史蒂芬・安布洛斯
编剧:布鲁斯・麦肯纳
导演:大卫・利兰
兄 弟 连
当我们向着巴斯通出发
When we left for Bastogne...
我们缺少装备 弹药不足
...we were short of equipment, we didn't have enough ammunition...
也没有足够的御寒衣物
...we didn't have enough warm clothes.
可是我们相信
But we had confidence...
我们的长官将会补给我们所需的物资
...that our higher military authorities would get to us whatever we needed.
那有座位于林线的山脊 我们在山脊上挖战壕
And there was a ridge with a tree line. We were dug in on that ridge.
德军很清楚我们在那儿 对我们进行猛烈炮轰
The Germans knew right where we were, and they really gave us a shellacking.
在巴斯通 我们曾经每人只剩一排子弹
Like in Bastogne, we were down to one round per man there for a while.
当地又起雾
The fog was in.
无法进行空投补给
They couldn't drop us or resupply us.
他们每次要对我们进行物资空投
Every time they tried to drop supplies in to us...
都会错过我们投给了德军
...they missed us and dropped them to the Germans.
有个家伙手臂被炮弹碎片击中
One of the guys got hit in the arm with a piece of shrapnel.
结果手肘以下全部炸断
Took his arm off above the elbow.
他们要将手臂截肢 他只说 "把我的手表拿下来"
And they were taking him out, he said, "Get my wristwatch off my arm."
然后一个医护兵来了 我想他真是救了我一命
And then a medic came along, and I think he really saved my life...
因为他在我的关键部位打了一针吗啡
...because he stuck a Syrette in a key position. Morphine.
即使是现在 当我们在寒夜上床睡觉时
Even today, a real cold night...
我太太会告诉你...
...we go to bed and my wife will tell you that...
我讲的第一句话是："很庆幸我不是在巴斯通"
...first thing I'll say is, "I'm glad I'm not in Bastogne."
第六集
巴 斯 通
蹲下 蹲下 蹲下!
Duck, duck, duck!
过来...快点!(德语)
Kommen Sie hier.
Kommen Sie hier, schnell!
快点!(德语)
Schnell!
医生 绷带
Doc, bandage.
带他回团部
Take him back to Regiment.
你们都知道麦考利夫将军现在是代师长
As you all know, General McAuliffe, Acting Division Commander.
把战况老实跟我说
Give it to me straight!
将军 我们占领了一个点
We've been taking ground in one position, General...
同时就又失去另一个点
...losing it in another.
现在看来形成僵局 我们正在森林边缘挖战壕
And now it looks like a standoff. We're digging in on the edge of the forest.
将军 我们遭遇到全面的炮火轰击
We're under sporadic artillery fire, General.
我们很多人受伤甚重却没有医疗站
We're taking a lot of hits, and we have no aid station.
我们的粮食耗尽 没有冬装
We've run out of food, we have no winter clothes...
仅有少量 甚至没有弹药
...and we have little or no ammo.
战线分布太宽 敌人可以利用缝隙溜进我们指挥所
The line's spread so thin, the enemy wanders into our CP to use our slit trenches, sir.
我们守不住整个战线
We just can't cover the line.
早安 尼克森上尉
Good morning, Captain Nixon.
你还有什么要跟麦考利夫将军报告的吗?
You got anything to add for General McAuliffe?
将军 有的
General, yes, sir.
将军 凌晨3点我到战线走了一趟
General, I took a walk along the line about 0300 last night.
却找不到右翼的501团
Couldn't find the 501st on our right flank.
我用我们第二排其中的一班去填补空缺
I tied in with a squad from our 2nd Platoon.
可是长官 我们的防线空隙实在是太大了
But, sir, we've got some considerable gaps in our perimeter.
我的人手不足 长官 我们分散得太广了
I don't have enough people, sir. We're spread too damn thin.
守住战线 上校 把缝隙填满
Hold the line, Colonel, close the gaps.
这场雾短期内不会散去
This goddamn fog won't lift any time soon...
所以你们也别指望空中支援
...so you can forget about air cover.
你们的第一营刚从佛依撤退 德军一路追击他们
Your 1st Battalion just pulled out of Foy, Krauts on their tail.
对方有坦克 炮兵 他们也没有后援
Tanks, artillery. Got no backup.
我们要遭遇的麻烦还真多
There's a lot of shit heading this way.
我可以从你医药箱里借条绷带吗 长官?
Can I scrounge a bandage from your aid kit, sir?
你现在情况如何?
How are you fixed?
没有血浆 几条绷带 可以说是没有吗啡
No plasma, couple of bandages. Practically no morphine.
事实上 我曾试着去三营拿些补给
I tried to find my way up to 3rd Battalion...
可是 我迷路了
...looking for supplies, but lost my way.
你如果找不到三营的话 那就联络莱恩医生
If you can't get over to 3rd, hook up with Doc Ryan.
他会尽可能的补给你
He'll fix you up with what he has to spare.
谢谢你 上尉
Thanks, Captain.
尤金 你能拿多少就拿多少
Eugene, get everything you can.
会派上用场的
You're gonna need it.
- 史宾纳? - 医生 - 出什么事了?
- Spina. - Doc. - What's happening?
- 我们在防线上挖战壕 - 是吗?
- We're digging in right along the line. - Yeah?
就这样
Yeah, this is it.
你拿到些什么?
So, what'd you get?
我拿到这个
I got this.
我还拿到条德军绷带
And I got myself a Kraut bandage.
什么? 就这些?
What, this is it?
对! 就这样 只有这些了
Yeah, that's it, that's all you got.
老天
Jesus
第一营撤出佛依了
You know, 1st Battalion's pulled out of Foy.
死伤惨重
Heavy casualties.
既然他们撤退了 我们还坐在这里干嘛?
If they're pulling back, why are we sitting here?
我们需要吗啡 我只剩这些
We need morphine, this is all I've got.
你有多一把剪刀吗?
You got extra scissors?
没有 只有这一支
Just the one.
- 李普军士长! - 长官
- First Sergeant Lipton! - Sir.
这是什么?
What's this?
- 两个医护兵在一个坑里? - 没错
- Two medics in one hole? - Yes, sir.
要是你们被一炮打中! 我们要怎么办?
What's gonna happen to us if you take a hit?
长官?
Sir?
军士长 我的散兵坑呢?
First Sergeant, where's my foxhole?
就在后面 长官
It's back here, sir.
或许您刚错过了
Maybe you missed it.
我带您回去 长官 你靠前线稍微近了点
I'll walk you back, sir. You're a bit close to the line here.
可恶
Goddamn it.
葛奈瑞中士! 你从荷兰带来的吗啡还有吗?
Sergeant Guarnere, did you keep your morphine from Holland?
不在了
No.
医生 我有话跟你说
Doc, I've gotta talk to you.
你腿怎么啦?
How's that leg?
去他的腿 我小便会痛!
To hell with the leg, I'm pissing needles.
待会儿再说...
Later.
可恶!
Shit!
有没有看到德军?
You seen them?
没有! 可他们就在那里
No. But they're out there.
相信我
Depend on it.
来杯咖啡吗 医生?
Cup of joe, Doc?
戈登 我需要剪刀
Gordon, I need scissors.
你有剪刀吗? 很利的剪刀
You got scissors, sharp scissors?
剪刀?
Scissors?
让我看看 我得去缝纫室找找
Well, let's see, I'll have to check the sewing room.
或许在楼上书房里
Might be upstairs in the study.
书桌中间细长老旧的抽屉里
That skinny drawer in the middle of the desk.
好吧! 你有没有多余的止痛药?
All right, what about an extra Syrette in your aid kit?
大伙儿把吗啡藏好
Hide your morphine, guys.
- 马克 你还好吧? - 我没事
- Muck, you all right? - I'm good!
马克 马拉其 找掩体
Muck, Malarkey, take cover! We're okay!
你们看看? 他们把我的头盔弄的全是灰
Take a look at this shit! They've peppered my helmet!
医生 吗啡
Doc, morphine.
拿去! 潘卡拉到哪儿去了?
Here, take it! Where's Penkala?
天知道
Christ knows.
医护兵~
Medic!
医生!
Doc!
- 医护兵! - 你们受伤了吗?
- Medic! - You guys hit?
医生 你在干什么? 你疯啦?
Doc, what are you doing? Are you crazy?
你盯着他看干什么? 看好你的战线
What are you looking at him for? Watch the goddamn line.
- 你有止痛针吗? - 没有
- You got a Syrette? - No.
医护兵!
Medic!
医生!
Doc!
潘卡拉
Penkala!
医生!是动脉 我感觉得到
Doc! It's the artery, I can feel it!
- 潘卡拉 放松 - 是动脉!
- Penkala, let go... - It's the goddamn artery!
潘卡拉 松开你的手指 可恶 快放松!
Penkala, loosen your fingers, goddamn it!
- 我会失血过多而死! - 松开手! 快点!
- I'll bleed to death. - Relax your arm, Penky!
- 不是动脉! - 我不要回去了 医生
- It's not the artery. - I ain't going back, Doc.
- 什么? - 在这种情况下我哪儿都不去
- What? - I ain't going nowhere, not in this shit.
你不想出去还喊医务兵?
You don't wanna go, and you yell medic?
我不想去没有医疗站的地方
I don't need to go back to no aid station.
算你运气好 潘卡拉 我们这儿也没有医疗站
You're in luck, Penkala, because we don't got no aid station.
潘卡拉 剪刀 你有剪刀吗?
Penkala, I need scissors. You got scissors?
我带剪刀干什么?
What the hell I need scissors for?
有带急救包吗?
Got your aid kit?
好 你现在还不需要这个
Right, you don't need this, not yet.
我比较需要
I do.
- 谁受伤了? - 潘卡拉
- Who got hit? - Penkala.
这样吧 我要你这么做
All right, this is what I want you to do.
我要你带个人想办法去三营
I want you to take someone and work your way to the 3rd Battalion.
我们需要绷带 血浆
You know what we need: Bandages, plasma.
你能讨什么都讨来 知道吗?
Whatever you can beg, you beg, all right?
还有给我拿剪刀来 我一把也没有
And get me some goddamn scissors. I can't get any.
你自己也弄个热餐吃
And you get yourself a hot meal, too.
去吧!
Go.
他说他还是处男
You know, he told me he was a goddamn virgin.
谁?
Who?
在我散兵坑里的新兵朱利安
The replacement in my foxhole, Julian.
是吗?
Yeah?
还是处男 根本只是个小孩
Goddamn virgin. Just a kid.
我唯一知道的处子是"圣母玛利亚"
The only virgin I know is the Virgin Mary.
贝比! 我们到底在哪儿?
Hey, Babe, where the hell are we?
往这边走
This way.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like it.
三营到底在哪儿?
Where the hell is 3rd Battalion?
糟糕
Shit!
快上来!
Come on.
- 快点 把手伸过来 - 快走!
- Come on, come on, give me a hand. - Go, go!
- 快点 史宾纳 快跑! - 我在跑
- Come on, Spina, move! - I'm moving!
跑快点 快点 跑
Get moving! Come on, go!
我们可以分一点绷带给你 但只有这些了
Okay, we can spare a few bandages, but that's it.
没有吗啡
No morphine.
你们得回巴斯通找血浆
You'll have to go back to Bastogne for plasma.
巴斯通? 我们花了一小时才找到你们
It took us an hour to find you.
你们的外科大夫没有血浆吗?
Doesn't your surgeon have plasma?
我们没有外科大夫 我们没有外科大夫 也没有医疗站 什么都没有
We don't have one. No surgeon, no aid station, nothing.
只有我跟我的伙伴
Just me and my buddy.
很抱歉 我们就是没有办法帮你们
Sorry, guys, but we just can't help you.
找掩体!
Take cover!
快离开这里 我们要撤退了!
Get your butts out of here! We're pulling back!
快点 我们走!
Come on, let's go!
快走!
Move!
真该一枪打烂那德佬的屁股 然后德佬也回一枪 让他屁股开花!
Should have shot Hinkle in the ass! And you would have shot him in the ass!
上帝保佑
God bless ya.
这闻起来像是我的腋窝
Yo, these smell like my armpit.
至少你的腋窝是温暖的
At least your armpit's warm.
那你要加糖浆吗?
Do you want syrup with that?
乔 你老实说 这里面放的到底是什么东西?
Joe, be honest. What's in these things anyway?
- 没有你不吃的 马拉其 - 我不吃马拉其
- Nothing you won't eat, Malarkey. - I won't eat malarkey.
也许德国佬会喜欢你那套
Maybe Hinkle would like your share?
- 我早该一枪毙了他 - 贝比 你会倒着跑吗?
- Should've shot him when I could. - Running backwards?
有人看到戴克中尉吗?
Anybody seen Lieutenant Dike?
问问看营指挥所 长官
Try Battalion CP, sir.
问问看巴黎
Try Paris.
问问看德国佬
Try Hinkle.
亲爱的德国佬 我回家了
"Hinkle, sweetie, I'm home."
尤金 戴克中尉有个完整的急救包 找他试试看
Eugene, Lieutenant Dike's got a full aid kit. Try him.
对 我相信他都还没有用到
Yeah, I'm sure he's not using his.
也许德佬有止痛针给你
Maybe Hinkle's got a Syrette for you.
吃你的馅饼 阿德仔 吃胳肢窝
Eat your strudel. Hinkle-vinkle, eat the armpit?
戴克中尉
Lieutenant Dike.
能分点急救包吗 长官? 我们很缺 需要止痛针
Can you spare something from your aid kit? I'm short. I need Syrettes.
- 要吗啡吗? - 是的 长官
- What, morphine? - Yes, sir.
如果我中弹怎么办?
What happens if I get hit?
我会来救你的 长官!
I'll be there, sir.
- 止痛针在里面 对吧? - 是的
- Syrettes in here, right? - Yes, it is.
给你
Here.
我不准备中弹的
I don't plan on getting hit.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
赫夫朗
Heffron.
赫夫朗 你还好吗?
Heffron, you okay?
尤金! 你叫我的姓干嘛?
Gene, what is with the Heffron bullshit?
你明知道我的名为何不用?
You know my name. Why don't you use it?
你叫爱德华 对不对?
It's Edward, right?
爱德华? 你是认真的吗? 只有修女会叫我爱德华
Edward? Are you serious? Only the goddamn nuns call me Edward.
听着 我要知道你还有没有从荷兰带来的吗啡?
I need to know if you kept your morphine from Holland.
你已经问过我了 还记得吗?
No, you asked me already, remember?
我不..不记得了
No, I don't recall.
戈登 你找我吗?
Gordon, you want me?
关于吗啡
Oh, yeah, morphine.
第三排把它用光了
3rd Platoon ponied up the contraband.
你还在找剪刀吗?
You still looking for scissors?
对
Yes, I am.
找派康提
Perconte.
派康提
Perconte?
医生
Doc.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你最好去观测所找乔托伊
And you'd better check on Joe Toye out on the OP.
他缺了些东西
He's missing something.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们还好吗?
You guys okay?
他们有热餐吃 闻到了吗?
They got hot food. Can you smell it?
- 托伊 你想要什么吗? - 回家
- Toye, are you missing something? - Home.
医生 叫他跳个舞
Ask him to dance, Doc.
托伊 你的脚给我看
Toye, show me your feet.
你给我看好前线 麦克朗
You watch the goddamn line, McClung.
- 你的靴子呢? - 在华盛顿 泰勒将军的屁股上
- Where are your boots? - In Washington, up General Taylor's ass.
- 我才不相信 - 我光脚比较好走 医生
- I don't believe this. - I can move better in bare feet, Doc.
发生什么事?
What happened?
我把靴子脱了想弄干袜子
I took them off to dry my goddamn socks.
结果被炸飞了
They got blown to hell, okay?
你穿几号?
What's your size?
9号 跟大家一样
Nine, just like everybody else.
法兰克! 你再刷牙 德军一里外就能看到你
Frank, you keep cleaning those teeth, the Germans will see you a mile away.
- 一枪毙了你! - 没错 小不点 你尽管笑吧
- Shoot you dead. - That's right, Pee Wee, you keep laughing.
医生
Hey, Doc.
我的东西
My stuff!
拜托 医生 你在开药店啊?
Come on, Doc. You got a drug store in here?
哪有 这都是我自己的
No, I own my stuff.
你在找什么?
What are you looking for?
剪刀 谢谢你 派康提
Scissors. Thank you, Perconte.
我的剪刀
My goddamn scissors!
- 葛奈瑞中士 - 马林 是你吗?
- Sergeant Guarnere. - Gene, is that you?
医生! 过来这里
Hey, Doc! Doc, come here!
劳军团来搜集止痛针 艾力、李高特 你们有吗?
USO. Picking up Syrettes. Alley, Liebgott, you got any?
没有 在荷兰用掉了
No, got used in Holland, Doc.
你没在用这玩意吧 医生? 我是说私人用途?
You ain't using this stuff, are you, Doc, personally?
得了
Come on.
医生 我还是会痒
Hey, Doc, I still got the itching.
每次尿尿都痛的要死
Every time I pee, it's murder.
我知道 很抱歉 我就是没有盘尼西林来治你兄弟
I'm sorry, but I don't have penicillin for your...
我的什么?
My what?
中尉! 你要走动让血液流动
Make sure you move around. Get your blood flowing.
我的脚麻了
I can't feel my feet.
对 所以你得走动一下 这样才不会得战壕脚
That's why you gotta move, so you don't get trench foot.
我要把靴子脱掉吗?
Should I take my boots off?
不用 只要松开走一走
All you gotta do is just loosen them up, keep moving.
抱歉 中士
Sergeant, I'm sorry.
我知道你很难受 可是我爱莫能助
Look, I know it must be hell, but I can't help you, all right?
你多喝水就是了
Just drink lots of water.
水? 我就是小便会痛啊!
Water? It's pissing that hurts!
安静!给我闭嘴!
Shut it! Shut the hell up!
这里是怎么回事 比尔? 是谁在唱歌?
What's going on here, Bill? Who the hell's singing?
我会查出来的 中尉 我会找出来 叫他们闭嘴
I'll find out, Lieutenant. I'll find out, I'll shut them up.
主啊 答应我今后无需再如此迫切寻求慰籍 与安慰别人
"Lord, grant that I shall never seek So much to be consoled as to console
被了解 去了解别人 被爱
"To be understood, as to understand Or to be loved
及全心爱人
"As to love with all my heart.
用我全心去爱
"With all my heart"
医护兵!
Medic!
- 派康提 叫吉普车来! - 快啊 医生
- Perconte, you getting a jeep? - I'm on it, Doc.
- 看他们怎么对待我的腿! - Ｅ连指挥部
- Look what they did to my leg! - Easy CP!
Ｅ连指挥部 我是派康提! 西斯克中弹 我需要辆吉普
Easy CP, this is Perconte. Sisk has been hit and I need a jeep.
再说一遍 我现在需要辆吉普车
I say it again, I need a jeep now!
他们在移动了 可恶 我们现在就要
They're moving, goddamn it! We need it now!
好了 西斯克 没有那么糟
Okay, Sisk, it ain't that bad.
没有那么糟?
Ain't that bad?
拉!
Pull!
不要 医生 留着吗啡 我撑得过来 我撑得过来 留着 好吗?
No, Doc, save the morphine, I can make it. I can make it, save it, okay?
好吧 我们带他离开这里
All right, let's get him out of here.
- 死吉普车在哪? - 我不知道 可我听到声音了
- Where's the goddamn jeep? - I don't know, but I hear it.
我的老天!
Jesus Christ!
史基尼 你的血沾的我满裤子都是
You got blood all over my trousers.
我真的很抱歉 法兰克
I'm real sorry, Frank!
把他扶起来
Get him up.
该死的
Damn it, Skinny.
告诉史宾纳我去找血浆
Tell Spina I went in for plasma.
来吧
Come on.
所有的坦克 炮兵都撤到这里来
All the tanks, artillery, are pulled back to here.
我们在巴斯通之外没有后援 就是这样了
We've got no backup beyond Bastogne. This is it.
德军俘虏了第326医疗营 带走了所有的人
The Krauts captured the 326th Medical, and they took everybody...
医生 医务兵 整个营
...doctors, medics, the whole shebang.
我们什么也不剩
We got nothing.
他们给弟兄们烈酒来止痛
They're giving the boys hooch for the pain.
他被迫击炮击中 注意他的腿
He took a mortar hit. Watch the leg.
- 对 小心我的腿 - 抬他进去
- Yeah, watch the leg. - Get him in.
- 让开! - 借过!
- Move it! - Coming through.
早 小伙子们
'Morning, fellas.
把他放到这里
No, no, here, put him here.
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
他严重吗?
Is he bad?
不 小腿受伤 没打吗啡
No, lower-leg wound, no morphine.
护士! 你有没有血浆可以让我...
Nurse, have you got plasma? I can...
请你等一下
Wait, please.
这里是怎么回事? 为什么这些人没有疏散?
What's going on here? Why aren't these men evacuated?
我们没法疏散 后路被切断了
We can't evacuate. We're cut off.
这是能撤得最远的地方了
This is as far as it goes.
注意血浆(法语)
Faites attention aux deplacements.
你好吗? (法语)
Ca va?
这不是最紧急的(法语)
Ce n'est pas grave, ce n'est pas urgent.
医生 我现在在天堂
I'm in heaven, Doc.
还没有 谢谢你(法语)
Pas encore, Dieu merci.
护士?
Nurse?
这边请
This way.
我需要吗啡和绷带 你有什么都给我
I need morphine, I need bandages, whatever you've got.
我可以给你分一些 但是不能太多
Okay, I can give you a little, but not a lot.
拿去吧 这个你拿走
There you go. You can have this today.
你要那个吗?
Do you want that?
要 你有血浆吗?
Wait. You got plasma?
一点点
A little.
你是外科大夫吗?
Are you a surgeon?
不是 我们没有外科大夫
No, we don't got no surgeon.
这是什么?
What's this?
从床上扯下来的
From the bed.
- 床单吗? - 对 当绷带用的
- What, sheets? - Yes, for bandages.
好
Yeah
- 都在这儿了 - 谢谢(法语)
- Voila. - Merci.
你叫什么名字? (法语)
Comment vous appelez-vous?
我叫芮妮
My name is Renee.
我叫尤金 尤金罗
I'm Gene, Eugene Roe.
你是哪里人?
Where are you from?
路易斯安那 1/4印第安血统
Louisiana, half-Cajun.
你呢? 你是哪里人? (法语)
Et toi, d'ou viens-tu?
巴斯通
Bastogne.
你可以载我回前线吗?
Can you get me back to the line?
当然
Sure.
尤金
Eugene.
巧克力(法语)
Chocolat.
给你的(法语)
Pour vous.
(拉丁祷文)
Benedictio dei omnipotentis patri et filii...
...et spiritus sancti descendat super vos...
(拉丁祷文)
...et maneat semper.
阿门! 阿门!
Amen. Amen.
好好为你的主及国家作战
Fight well for your God and your country.
上帝祝福你们 一切小心
God bless you all, and stay safe.
就这样了 各位 没什么好再担心的
That's it, guys, nothing more to worry about.
我们就是要死了 也要在祥和的状态下死去
We're gonna die now, we're gonna die in a state of grace.
是不是这样 贝比?
Isn't that right, Babe?
营部要派一个侦察任务
Battalion want a reconnaissance patrol.
寻找德军
Kraut hunting.
好 我去 拿着这些
All right, I'll go. Take these.
把靴子给乔托伊 告诉他这是9号的
Give the boots to Joe Toye. Tell him they're a nine.
一直走 直到我们与敌方遭遇为止
Keep going, till we make some kind of contact.
- 皮卡克带队 是不是? - 是的
- Peacock's leading, right? - Right.
这笨蛋啥都找不到
Asshole couldn't find a snowball in a blizzard.
情况就是这样 这是命令
That's what's happening, that's the order.
- 中士! - 什么事 朱利安
- Sarge? - Yeah, Julian.
让我当尖兵
Let me be the lead scout.
归队 二等兵
Back of the line, Private.
- 好 就这样 我们出发了! - 成战术纵队 各位
- All right, that's it, let's move out. - Tactical columns, gentlemen.
医生 医生 这是战斗巡逻
Doc, it's a combat patrol.
你何不退后免得惹祸 好吗?
Why don't you stay back and keep your ass out of trouble?
好的 中士
Yes, sir. Yeah.
快点 胡伯勒 赶上来
Come on, Hoobler, pick it up.
前进
Right, move on.
走
Go.
- 开火!(德语) - 快趴下!
- Fire! - Get down! Get down!
老天
Jesus!
可恶!
Shit!
大牛! 克里斯登生!
Bull! Christenson!
到战线上!
Up on line!
强尼!
Johnny!
我们有人中弹了
We got a man down!
杰克?
Jack, over here.
情况如何?
What have we got?
- 不要动 朱利安! - 我们得离开这里!
- Keep still, Julian! - We've gotta make a move!
我可以去救他 中士
I can get him, Sarge.
压制火力!
Suppressing fire!
Ｅ连指挥所 有人中弹倒地!
One man down, Easy!
压制火力!
Covering fire!
Ｅ连指挥所 有人中弹倒地!
Easy CP, I have one man down!
待在那里不要动
Okay, stay there, don't move!
不然他们会开枪打你
Stop moving, or else they'll keep shooting!
发生什么事 长官?
What's happening, sir?
我们要撤退了
We're pulling back.
我们遭遇德军 我得回到指挥部
We made contact. I gotta get to the CP.
别动! 他们会继续射击的 不要动! 不要动!
Don't move! Stop moving! They'll keep firing! Stop moving!
可恶
Jesus Christ, fuck it!
- 约翰 - 什么?
- John! - What?
撤退 我们得撤退了!
Pull back, we gotta pull back!
- 我们快走吧! - 我们走!
- Let's get the hell out of here! - Let's go, let's go!
走了!
Move! Go!
你要撑着!
Stay with us, stay with us!
撑着 朱利安!看着我 撑下去!
Hold on, Julian! Stay with us! Look at me, stay with us!
撑着!
Look at me, hold on, hold on!
别动 朱利安 我们会回来的!
Don't move, Julian, we're coming back!
我们会救你回去的 撑下去!
We'll get you out of here, just hold on!
走 我们走!
Go! Let's go!
快走!
Move!
- 快点 我们走! - 我们到底在哪儿?
- Come on, let's go! - Where the hell are we?
往前直走! 往前直走!
Straight ahead, straight ahead!
医生!
Doc!
克里斯登生 把它架在石头上
Okay, Christenson set it up on the rock.
Ｅ连指挥所 这是闪电
Easy CP, Easy CP, lightning. Over.
我需要吉普车在指挥所待命
I need an A-jeep standing by at the CP.
好了 帮你弄到吉普车了 医生
Okay, got you a jeep, Doc.
马丁!
Martin!
- 长官! - 发生什么事?
- Sir! - What's going on?
他们打中朱利安!
They got Julian!
- 他还活着! - 我们并不确定!
- He's still alive! - We don't know that!
- 得去救他 长官! - 遭遇的是敌军观测所还是锋线?
- We gotta go get him! - Did you hit an OP or their line?
是锋线 长官!
Their line, sir!
我们得回去把朱利安救出来!
We've gotta go back, get Julian out of there!
- 不 回防! - 我们找不到皮卡克
- No, fall back! - We lost Peacock.
- 他回到指挥所了 - 快点 马丁 回防线上!
- No, he's back at the CP. - Come on, Martin, fall back!
叫他们都离开!
Get him out of here!
我们快走吧!
Let's up and go!
医生 我们现在得走了
Doc, we've gotta move now, Doc. Come on, let's go!
来吧 我们走!
Doc, now, let's go!
快走!
Move!
- 我们走! - 退回去!
- Let's go! - Fall back!
我们救不了他 上尉
We couldn't get to him, Captain.
我们尽力了 贝比也尽力了 就是救不了他
We tried. Babe tried. We couldn't get to him.
大伙儿
People
让我跟你们一起坐
Let me sit in here with you guys.
赫夫朗?
Heffron?
托伊
Toye.
你在这里干什么?
What you doing out here?
谢谢你的靴子 医生 我现在很好
Thanks for the boots, Doc. Doing fine.
你的脚还是有问题吗?
Are you still having trouble with your feet?
给我看 让我看看
Show me, let me see it.
这是战壕脚 托伊
It's trench foot, Toye.
如果长了坏疽就要截肢了
If it turns gangrene, you could lose it.
医生 我绝不从战线上退下
I ain't coming off the line, Doc.
你得保持干燥
You gotta stay dry.
按摩你的脚
Massage your feet.
每天更换袜子 把湿袜子围在脖子弄干
Change socks every day and dry the wet ones around your neck.
- 试试看 - 必须做到
- Trying. - Do it.
我正在努力
I'm working on it.
- 你有看到赫夫朗吗? - 没有
- You seen Heffron? - No.
怎么了?
Why?
他不在他的坑里
He ain't in his hole.
可恶
Fuck.
找到你了
Got you.
赫夫朗?
Heffron?
爱德华
Edward?
吃吧
Eat it.
很好
Good.
非常好
Perfect.
我答应过他 如果他中弹了...
I promised him, if he got hit...
我会把他的东西带回去给他妈
...I'd get his stuff and bring it to his ma, you know?
现在那些混帐德国佬会把他给剥光
Now the fucking Krauts will strip him.
不会有事的
No, it's okay.
怎么会! 一定有事的
It's not! It's not okay.
应该回去救他的
I should've got to him.
你怎么称呼那些...半印第安血统的医疗师?
What do you call those people again? Those Cajun healers?
巫医
Traiteurs.
我的祖母就是位巫医
You know, my grandma was a traiteur.
你祖母? 没开玩笑?
Your grandmother? No shit?
是的
She was.
只要把手放在病人身上就治好他们
Laid her hands on people and cured them.
带走疾病...癌症...什么都行
Took away sickness, cancer, you name it.
你祖母真做的到? 别唬我了!
Your grandma did that? You're shitting me.
我记得她常祷告
I remember she used to pray a lot.
是啊 我想她一定得这么做
Yeah, I guess she had to.
告诉上帝她要移除的病痛
Talked to God about the pain she pulled out.
央求神明
Asked him to...
把病痛带走
...carry it away.
她就是这么做的
That's what she did.
天啊
Jesus.
我还在想为什么他们会挑我当医护兵
I'm still trying to figure why they picked me for a medic.
天晓得
God knows.
手指一指 就这样成了医护兵
Snap of a finger, and just like that, you're a medic.
我已经受够扮医生了
I've had enough playing doctor.
你呢?
How about you?
乔
Joe.
找掩护
Take cover
停止射击!
Cease fire!
停止射击 可恶!
Cease fire, goddamn it!
中士 我不懂 那不是我们的飞机吗?
Sergeant, I don't understand! It was our own planes!
是Ｃ－47
C-47's.
他们带来补给了 这是空投
They're bringing supplies. It's a drop.
这是空投 快来!
It's a drop, come on!
好了 去帮医生忙
All right, help the doc.
其他人跟我来
The rest of you come with me.
医务兵!
Medic!
谁来帮帮我们?
Someone give us a hand here!
帮个忙!
Help, help!
这个从这边穿过去
This one through here.
快点!
Now, vite!
(法语)
Fais pression, essaie de trouver I'artere.
Oui, d'accord.
我们得找出动脉
The artery, gotta find the artery!
我找不到!(法语)
Moi, je ne la trouve pas!
安娜!
Anna!
我找不到!(法语)
Je ne la trouve pas!
她打哪儿来的?
Where does she come from?
那个黑人女孩?
The black girl?
刚果
The Congo.
她怎么会来到这里?
How'd she get here?
跟我一样
Just like me.
她来帮忙的
She came to help.
巧克力? (法语)
Chocolat?
怎么了?
What?
你的手
Your hands.
我的手?
My hands?
你是个好护士
You're a good nurse.
我不是
No.
我不想再处理伤兵了
I never want to treat another wounded man again.
我宁愿在肉铺里工作
I'd rather work in a butcher shop.
可是你的触碰
But your touch...
让人镇定
...calms people.
这是上天给的天赋
That's a gift from God.
不 这不是天赋
No, it's not a gift.
上帝不会给人那么痛苦的东西
God would never give such a painful thing.
护士!
Nurse!
我们这里需要帮忙!
We need some help over here!
有人胃部被打穿了
Guy's shot through the stomach.
有多严重
How bad is it?
好 先把这人抬进去
Okay, get this one in first.
你会没事的 你会熬过来的
You'll be all right.
我现在知道他们的感受了
Now we know how they felt.
什么? 谁?
What? Who?
高卢外籍军团的战士
The legionnaires...
当他们看着匈奴人
...when they were watching the Huns...
哥德人及西哥特人
...the Goths, the Visigoths.
西哥特人?
Visigoths? Jesus Christ.
就是那些野蛮人
Barbarians.
他们以前就从这里经过
They came right through here.
就是从这些树丛之间穿过
Right through these trees, just sweeping down...
一路扫荡直奔罗马焚城
...to burn the shit out of Rome.
那路程可真遥远啊!
That's a hell of a long ride.
你的大学生活如何 巴克?
So what's college like, Buck?
你能有空念书吗? 当...
You got time to hit the books...
啦啦队员拨弄着你的头发
...with cheerleaders running their fingers through your hair?
天啊 贝比 我竟然不记得了
Hell, Babe I can't even remember.
是医生
Hey, it's Doc.
- 中士! - 赫夫朗
- Sergeant. - Heffron.
中尉
Lieutenant.
包扎一下
Wrap up.
他从不叫大家的绰号
Never calls anybody by their nickname.
他有次叫我爱德华
He once called me Edward.
真的?
Is that right?
你的本名叫爱德华?
Edward? That's your name?
是
Yeah.
好玩
Funny.
你看来不像是个"爱德华"
You don't look like an Edward.
医生
Hey, Doc.
看来又有得忙了
It's gonna get busy, pal.
不要射击 弟兄们 别上当暴露你们位置
Hold your fire, boys. Don't let them draw you out.
- 不要射击! - 大家保持待命
- Hold your fire! - Stay ready, boys.
我们要用什么来打那些玩意 李普?
What the hell are we gonna hit those things with, Lip?
不要射击! 准备好 华特
Hold your fire! Get ready, Walter!
留在散兵坑里
Stay in your holes, guys.
史摩基中弹了 医护兵!
Smokey's hit! Medic!
尤金! 我们走!
Eugene, let's go!
- 快点 我们走! - 好
- Come on, let's go! - Okay.
走!
Go!
准备
Ready.
医护兵!
Medic!
医生! 史摩基!
Doc! Smokey!
阿摩
Hi, Mo.
我来拿 我会帮你保管
I got it, I'm keeping it for you.
我的脚没知觉了 尤金
Smoke! I can't feel my legs, Gene.
放松 去我的散兵坑拿血浆 快去
Take it easy. My foxhole, get the plasma, now!
他们来了!
Here they come!
- 你一人来弄? - 我来弄 快去!
- You got them? - I got them. Go!
机枪群开火!
Machine guns, open fire!
转换射击阵地!
Open fire!
李普军士长!
Sergeant Lipton!
医生 我们得离开这里
Doc, we gotta get the hell out of here.
撑下去 史摩基! 撑下去!
Stay with us, Smokey. Stay with us!
我们得快离开!
We gotta get the hell outta here!
准备好了吗?
You ready?
好了 走!
All right, go!
- 停 我们得停一下 - 好的
- Stop, we've gotta stop. - All right.
- 拿着血浆 - 好的
- Take the plasma. - All right.
撑着 华特
Come on, Walt.
挺着 兄弟
Come on, buddy.
快点医生 我得回到战线上
Hurry, Doc, come on, Doc. I've gotta get back to the line.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
- 李普? - 我在听
- Lip? - Yeah, buddy.
你踩到我的手了
You're standing on my hand.
对不起 兄弟
Sorry.
听好 我会再颁个紫心勋章给你
Look, I'll get you another Purple Heart for it.
帮我们个忙
Give us a hand!
我帮你弄到车了 医生
I got you a ride, Doc.
琼斯!
Jones!
放在这儿
Give it here.
好了 把他放在这里
Okay, put him here.
他的兵籍牌呢?
Where's his tag?
他的兵籍牌呢? 他是怎么了?
Where's his tag? What's wrong with him?
瘫痪了
Paralyzed.
什么?
What?
他瘫痪了
He's paralyzed.
没有任何感觉
Can't feel a thing.
以圣父圣子圣灵之名
"In the name of the Father of the Son and of the Holy Spirit
阿门
"Amen"
尤金?
Eugene?
- 你要... - 芮妮 这里需要帮忙
- Are you... - Renee, I need some help here.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
芮妮
Renee!
这个给你
Here you go, man.
- 一份给医生 - 好的
- One for the doc? - Sure.
医生?
Doc?
这总比坐在师指挥所吃圣诞火鸡餐和烈酒好
Better than sitting down to a Christmas Eve dinner of turkey and hooch back at the division CP.
我就是爱吃野战口粮与臭豆子罐头
Damned if I don't like old Joe Domingus' rancid-ass beans better.
- Ｅ连将士们好啊! - 长官好!
- Hello, Easy Company. - Hello, sir.
长官好
Hello, sir.
麦考利夫将军发布了一个消息给整个师
General McAuliffe sent a message to the entire division.
我想你应该让大家知道
I thought maybe your people would like to hear it.
长官 这是你的特权
That should be your prerogative, sir.
好
All right.
兄弟们!
Men!
麦考利夫将军祝我们大家圣诞节愉快
General McAuliffe wishes us all a Merry Christmas.
你们会问这有什么值得快乐的?
"What's merry about all this, you ask.
就是这些
"Just this.
我们已经阻止了来自东西南北四方来的攻势
"We've stopped cold everything that's been thrown at us from the north, east, south and west.
两天前德军指挥官 要求我们光荣投降...
"Now, two days ago the German commander demanded our honorable surrender...
以免被包围的美军遭到全部歼灭
"...to save the USA encircled troops from total annihilation.
德军指挥官收到如下的回复
"The German commander received the following reply:
给德军指挥官
"'To the German commander:
神经病!
"'Nuts! '
我们给了国家以及在家乡所爱的人 一个有价值的圣诞礼物
"We're giving our country and our loved ones at home a worthy Christmas present.
我们有幸参与这场英勇的圣战
"And being privileged to take part in this gallant feat of arms...
我们真正为自己创造了...快乐圣诞!
"...we're truly making for ourselves a merry Christmas."
祝大家圣诞快乐 上帝保佑你们
Merry Christmas to you all, and God bless you.
圣诞快乐 长官
Merry Christmas, sir.
神经病!
Nuts!
( 德语歌声"平安夜" )
比尔
Bill.
我女友照片
Picture of my girl.
很漂亮的小妞 巴克
Good looking broad, Buck.
她...
She's...
她已经跟我分手了
She's finished with me.
是吗?
Yeah?
对
Yeah.
对啊 她是...
Yeah, she's...
刚好赶上圣诞节 对吧?
Just in time for Christmas.
刚好赶上圣诞节
可恶! 我差点忘了!
Shit! I almost forgot.
- 好彩牌香烟才是好料 - 你打哪儿弄来的?
- Lucky Strikes means fine tobacco. - Where the hell did you get those?
大家圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas, fellas.
该谢谢快乐的老圣人鲁兹
Gotta thank jolly old Saint Luz.
棒呆了
Beautiful.
拿去吧 潘卡拉
There you go, Penk.
我抖的太厉害 感觉好像在跳舞
I am shaking so goddamn much I feel like I'm dancing.
拿去抽吧!
There you go, buddy. There you go.
法兰克! 你在干什么?
Frank, what are you doing?
今天是圣诞节 小不点
It's Christmas, Pee Wee.
拿去 法兰克
Here, Frank.
- 这是什么? - 柠檬口味刨冰
- What is it? - Lemon-powder snow cone.
免了! 去他的圣诞快乐
Pass. Merry fucking Christmas.
哈利
Harry.
- 生火可不是好主意 - 几分钟就好
- Fire's not a good idea. - Just a couple of minutes.
我们在林中谷地
We're in a dell.
林中谷地?
A dell?
仙子和矮人住的地方?
Like where fairies and gnomes live?
我发誓闻到升火的味道
I swear I thought I could smell a fire.
我是闻到升火
I did smell a fire.
你们疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
我们位于林中谷地
We're in a dell.
卧倒!
Down! Crossfire!
上帝啊 不!
God, no!
这是尼克森上尉 第二营指挥部需要一辆吉普车
This is Captain Nixon. I need an A-jeep for Second Battalion CP.
- 哈利 不要动 - 医生 把火弄熄!
- Stay still, Harry. - Doc, put that out!
重复 第二营指挥部需要一辆吉普车
Repeat, A-jeep for Second Battalion CP.
医护兵!
Medic!
医生!
Doc!
快点 医生
Come on, Doc.
- 他受伤了吗? - 不知道
- Is he hurt? - I don't know.
隐蔽!
Move, get in!
医生!
Doc!
我得走了
I gotta go.
尤金 快点 起来 上尉在喊了
Eugene, come on, get up. The captain's yelling.
- 快点站起来 - 好
- Come on, get up. - Okay.
好 快起来 不是躺下
Okay, get up! Not lie down!
快点起来了! 快点! 我的天!
Okay, get up, come on, move! Jesus Christ!
我的手 可恶!
My hand, my goddamned hand!
罗!
Roe!
老天!
Jesus!
还好吗?
Okay.
罗?
Roe?
躺着别动 哈利
Stay still, Harry.
这只是擦伤 没那么简单就可以离开战场
Just a scratch. You're not getting out this easy.
吉普车在路上了 忍着点 这里有毛巾
Jeep's on it's way. Hang tough. Here's a towel.
毛巾
Towel.
好的
Yeah sure.
我袋子里有吗啡 给他用
I got morphine in my pocket. Give it to him.
- 你要打在哪儿? - 另一侧大腿
- Where you want it? - Opposite thigh.
好了
Okay.
抬高他的头
Elevate his head.
把他抬起来
Get him up.
这个给你 阿兵哥 拿着
There you go, soldier, take that.
进城去弄个热餐吃
Eugene, get yourself into town, get a hot meal.
让开!
Get out, quick!
快让路!
Clear the road!
快让开!
Get out, quick!
快离开那里
Stay out of there!
继续前进!
Keep moving!
医护兵!
Medic!
赶快出来帮忙!
Get your ass out here!
快点!
Come on!
每个整点都用无线电找你 我根本不知你在哪
Every hour, on the hour, on the radio, but I don't know where the hell you are.
一切还好吗?
Everything okay?
贝比?
Babe?
很好
Yeah.
你是怎么弄的?
How'd you do that?
是你弄的
You did that.
我来帮你包扎
I'll fix it up.
尤金 你刚叫我贝比
Hey, Gene. You called me Babe.
我有吗?
I did?
什么时候?
When?
就是刚才
Just now.
贝比
Babe.
我想我是这么叫你的
I guess I did.
贝比
Babe.
赫夫朗 你看好前线
Heffron, watch the goddamn line.
1944年12月28日
巴顿将军的第三集团军突破德军防线
使得补给能够送达并撤退伤员
我们今日所谓的"突出部之役"
正是描述巴顿将军前来救援被包围的101空降师
而101师没有任何官兵认为自己需要援救